# **Paul Lim**

#### **Data Scientist - Metis**

San Francisco Bay Area, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Paul-Lim/1ebe4d2df8e0bee4

Data scientist with a passion for sports biometrics. My background is in the environmental consulting, research, and food & beverage sectors.

Experience using machine learning, data mining, and statistical methods. Proficient in Python, SQL, and Matlab.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Data Scientist**

Metis - San Francisco, CA - April 2017 to Present

Developed five business-applicable data science projects, which utilized statistical inference, data acquisition, machine

learning techniques, supervised, unsupervised learning, Flask, D3.js, and MongoDB.

#### Staff Scientist

RPS Iris Environmental - Oakland, CA - August 2016 to March 2017

- Processed laboratory analytical data to create searchable databases and concise summary tables that are compared to federal or state regulated screening levels.
- Assisted client's Environmental Health & Safety team with developing safety training courses and fitting lab spaces to be in compliance with federal regulations.

#### Packaging Systems Engineering Intern

E&J Gallo Winery - Modesto, CA - January 2015 to July 2015

- Conducted laboratory experiments for Quality Control and Quality Assurance while applying Good Manufacturing Practices.
- Used design of experiments (DOE) to collect CO2 degradation data and fit a 2nd order polynomial regression model to the training data with an R-squared value of ~0.85. The model was used to validate the marketed shelf-life of carbonated wines.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B.S. in Chemical Engineering**

University of California 2016

### SKILLS

Python (1 year), SQL (1 year), Machine Learning (1 year), Data Analysis (1 year), Data Mining (1 year)

# LINKS

https://github.com/plim0793/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/plim0793/